<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Tech Blogs on Taha Husain</title>
    <link>https://tahahusain.me/posts/tech/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tech Blogs on Taha Husain</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 15:12:17 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://tahahusain.me/posts/tech/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>React Table - How to implement row selection with controlled server-side pagination</title>
      <link>https://tahahusain.me/posts/tech/react-table-row-selection-with-controlled-pagination/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 15:12:17 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tahahusain.me/posts/tech/react-table-row-selection-with-controlled-pagination/</guid>
      <description>In this blog, we will implement multi-row selection and select all with controlled server-side pagination in React using React Table hooks.
We will use examples provided by react-table for controlled pagination and row selection and pagination and work our way to acheive desired result.
Implementation Step 1 To select all rows, we would need unique identifier of all rows pre-fetched on the page. Pass all ids to the Table component.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Capybara with Rspec - How to find and assert fields</title>
      <link>https://tahahusain.me/posts/tech/capybara-with-rspec-how-to-find-and-assert-fields/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2021 11:45:14 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tahahusain.me/posts/tech/capybara-with-rspec-how-to-find-and-assert-fields/</guid>
      <description>Capybara provides find_field API to find input fields.
find_field(&#39;id_of_checkbox&#39;, type: &#39;checkbox&#39;) To add assertions for input fields we can use Rspec matcher have_field which has similar usage as find_field.
expect(page).to have_field(&#39;id_of_checkbox&#39;, type: &#39;checkbox&#39;) In some cases input fields are not found using find_field, specially when input field(s) are added by third party library.
Let&amp;rsquo;s take an example of toggle component that we recently used to understand this problem better.
&amp;lt;Toggle id=&amp;quot;toggleId&amp;quot; name=&amp;quot;toggleName&amp;quot; size=&amp;quot;large&amp;quot; isDisabled={disableToggle} value={toggleValue} isChecked={toggleValue} onChange={handleToggleChange} /&amp;gt; Adding above component in react code generates following HTML.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>React Datepicker - How to select Date and time in UTC</title>
      <link>https://tahahusain.me/posts/tech/react-datepicker-how-to-select-date-time-in-utc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Sep 2021 11:28:55 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tahahusain.me/posts/tech/react-datepicker-how-to-select-date-time-in-utc/</guid>
      <description>By default, React Datepicker selects date and time in local timezone. To select date in a specified timezone we need to convert timezone manually. To do so, we may also need to use library like Moment Timezone.
This blog focuses on selecting date and time in standard UTC timezone and its implementation doesn&amp;rsquo;t require extra library installation.
The original implementation is suggested by @JohnStarich. This implementation has a bit of tweak to accommodate time picker.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
